The landscape around here has become a lot spikier.
辺の景色も刺々しくなってきたな
Our depth is...
深度は
Let's see...
6,750 meters, I think.
6750メートルかな
Riko, I can see something down there!
リコ 下に何か見える
It's the Goblet of Giants!
巨人の盃だ
It's fine - it's just hot water.
大丈夫 ただのお湯だ
Still, it is terribly humid here.
しかし 凄まじい湿気だな
The goblets of giants...
巨人の盃 ダイラカズラが出してるんだよ
the flat-creepers are responsible for that.
I also hear the landscape is blue due to the mixing of
the vapor they put off with the light from the force field.
景色が青いのも
これが出す湯気と力場の光が混ざったせいらしいよ
Oh...
ほほう
You know, the part that supports the flat-creepers
is actually a different plant.
ダイラカズラはね 支えてる部分は別の植物なんだよ
The prey-trapping mechanisms of all these creepers
stretching out before us wither up every 2,000 years...
今広がってるこのカズラの捕食器は 2千年ごとに枯れちゃうんだけど
But it's said that then the plants below
all compete to grow,
そしたら下にある植物が競って生えて全然違う景色を作るんだって
giving rise to a completely new landscape.
これが 捕食器なのか
So those are prey-trapping mechanisms?
Amazing...
すごい すごいな
It's quite amazing...
We actually made it here to a place like this.
こんな所までこれたんだ
Compared to how I envisioned it in my dreams,
it's so much damper.
夢で見たのよりずっと 湿ってるよ
And my voice echoes like CRAZY!
声がのわぁんって響く
匂いも何か酸っぱい
It smells kinda vinegary here, too.
レグ 行こ
Reg, let's go!
Riko...
リコ
We need to find a decent place and make camp.
ちゃんとしたとこ見つけてキャンプしないと
You might not say it out loud,
but I'm sure you understand...
口には出さないが わかっているんだろう
That no matter how much we gloss over it,
this place is right in the belly of the netherworld.
どんなに取り繕っても ここは奈落の腹の中だ
The strain of ascending in the fourth layer
makes you bleed out of every orifice in your body.
四層の上昇負荷は全身の穴から血を吹かせる
It truly is a curse...
まさに「呪い」
If Riko's body was to undergo that, it's likely that...
リコの身体でそれうければ おそらくは
No matter what...
絶対に 守り抜け
protect her!
The fourth layer...
深界四層
Commonly referred to as part of "the depths,"
the probability of returning from this layer is so low
俗に深層と呼ばれるこの層の帰還率は
that the third layer can't even begin to compare.
三層の比較にならぬほど低い
Sprawling out here are the netherworld's goblets,
which fill up with and spill out
広がるのは様々な命と想いをたたえこぼす 奈落の盃
various lives and aspirations.
Will those who reach out their hands
be presented with fine spirits that quench their thirst,
手を伸ばす者達に与えられるのは渇き潤す美酒か
それとも身を焼く毒か
or will they instead receive a burning poison?
Daremo ga sakaraezu ni mogutteiku
誰もが逆らえずに潜っていく
その目を灯火より輝かせて
Sono me o tomoshibi yori kagayakasete
Mezasu saki wa fukaku
目指す先は深く まっすぐに迷い込む
Massugu ni mayoikomu
口開けた奈落の罠 真実の跡を追いかけよう
Kuchiaketa naraku no wana
Shinjitsu no ato o oikakeyou
Ima kotae ga mitsukaru nara zenbu nakushitemo ii
今答えが 見つかるなら 全部失くしてもいい
Sono koe o hanasanai youni kodama ga mada hibiiteru
その声を 離さないように 木霊がまだ響いてる
羅針盤はずっと 闇を指したまま逃げ場のない 方へ
Rashinban wa zutto
Yami o sashita mama
Nigeba no nai
Hou e
Sore ga noroi demo
それが呪いでも 鼓動は本物
Kodou wa honmono
二度と憧れは 止まらない
Nidoto akogare wa tomaranai
Poison and the Curse
The final section of the third layer
had those spiky eggs, right?
三層の最後にトゲトゲの卵があったでしょ
Yeah...
あれが孵ってね
If one hatches...
I hear it'll become one of those squid-looking things.
あのイカみたいなのになるんだって
That species still hasn't been given a name, though...
あの種類はまだ名前が付けられてないんだけど
But, you know, less than ten percent of
the creatures in the Abyss have even been named.
でもね アビスの生き物で名前がついてるのってまだ一割もいないの
There are tens of thousands of species that-
そんで何万て種類が
Shh!
What's wrong?
どうしたの
Never mind...
いや すまない
I'm sorry.
For a little while now,
I've been sensing a strange presence...
先ほどから妙な気配がしてな
Huh?
なぁに 生き物
What is it? A creature?
Don't tell me it's a White Whistle...
まさか 白笛
It only moves while we're talking.
僕らがしゃべっている間だけ動いているんだ
It's not moving right now...
今は動きがないが 恐らく耳のいい
But it very likely has good hearing...
And I bet it can understand our speech, too.
それも言葉を理解しているものじゃなかろうか
I suppose it could be also be another cave raider
other than just a White Whistle...
白笛だけじゃなくて ほかの探窟家も考えられるけど
It's certainly strange...
どうも妙だ
I can't even begin to pin down its position.
こちらから全く位層が掴めない
It's kind of eerie...
なんだか不気味だね
この場所離れたほうがいいかも
Maybe we should get out of this place...
Good idea!
よしきた
These "umbrellas" and the steam provide good cover,
but walking here is difficult and visibility's bad.
この傘と湯気はいい隠れ蓑になるが
歩きにくいし視界も悪いな
Riko, you alright?
リコ 大丈夫か
Yeah...
At the very least, we need to find
somewhere we can camp.
せめてキャンプが出来るとこ見つけなきゃね
どうしたのレグ
What's the matter, Reg?
Was it this one?!
こいつか
No, don't!
だめ レグ逃げて
Reg, run!
That's an orbed-piercer!
そいつ「タマウガチ」だ
Reg, don't fight it!
レグ 相手にしちゃだめ
I was told that an orbed-piercer's spines
can penetrate even steel...
タマウガチの針は鋼も通すって言われてて
They're also laced with poison, and more than
one hundred cave raiders have already been kill-
それに毒も混ざってて 今まで100人以上の探窟家が殺され
I didn't sense it until it got close!
近づかれるまで気配がなかった
So this is a beast of the depths, huh?!
あれが深層の獣か
Wha...?!
な リュックが
The backpack...!
I thought I dodged that...
避け切ったと思ったのに
速い いや
It's fast!
Or rather...
退路を読んだんだ
it predicted my line of retreat!
レグ ブレイズリーブが
Reg, the Blaze Reap is...!
It's down by its feet!
奴の足元か マズイな
This is bad...
What's with this creature?!
なんだ あいつは
Does it actually know what that thing is?!
あれがなんだかわかっているというのか
Be careful, Reg!
気をつけてレグ
The primeval creatures of the depths that
Ozen was talking about have amazing intuition like that.
オーゼンさんが言ってた深界の原生生物は ああいう勘がすごくいいって
Here it comes!
来るか
Reg, take this!
レグ これ
It should recoil from things bigger than itself!
あいつ自分より大きものに怯むの
So, use this Scaled Umbrella!
だから このウロコ傘で
Alright!
ようし
Halt!
とまれ
I-I don't think that thing was nearly big enough...
お 大きさが全然足りないじゃないか
It didn't work, Riko!
だめだリコ
一旦プレイズリープの辺まで動こ
Let's make our way toward the Blaze Re-
R-Reg...
レ レグ ど 毒が
Th-the poison will...
We need something to constrict it...
何か縛るもの
S-sorry, Reg...
ご ごめんね レグ
Reg!
レグ
Riko, this is going to hurt a little.
リコ 少し痛むぞ
What should I do?!
どうする
Riko, hold out your arm.
リコ 腕を出して
What do I have to do to save Riko?!
どうすれば リコを助けられる
The Blaze Reap is...!
ブレイズリーブは
Damn!
くそ
It's submerged...
水没してしまっている
Even if I act as a decoy,
Riko can't search for it in her current state.
僕が囮になっても 今のリコには 探せない
My Incinerator?!
火葬砲
No!
だめだ 二時間も昏倒してリコはどうなる
If I faint for two hours, what will become of Riko?!
Escape...
逃げる 逃げるしかない
Escaping is our only option.
However, given its quickness
and ability to predict our movements...
しかしあの素早さと先読み
we won't be able to shake it by running.
走っては振り切れない
If that's the case...
だとすれば
Up it is!
上だ
But, the strain of ascending in the fourth level is...
しかし 四層の上昇負荷は
intense pain throughout the body and bleeding...
全身の激痛と流血
Riko!
リコ
Do it... Please.
やって お願い
Y-you say that, but...
そ そうは言うが
Please!
お願い
I'm sorry, Reg.
ごめんね レグ
Seems... I don't have... much time...
もう 時間がないみたいなの
Riko, pull yourself together! Riko!
リコ しっかりしろ リコ
Please wake up!
目を覚ましてくれ
Reg...
レグ
Reg, what's the matter?
レグ どうしたの
I feel kinda strange....
なんか変だな
Riko, what are you talking about?
I feel kinda strange....
何言ってるんだ しっかりしろ
Riko, what are you talking about?
Get a hold of yourself!
Oh?
It doesn't hurt that much...
あんまり痛くない
What is this?!
なあにこれ
Riko, doesn't it seem like the Curse of the Abyss caused
the poison to be expelled first before your own blood?
リコ「アビスの呪い」で 血が出る代わりに
まず毒が出たのではないか
I see...
そっかぁ
Well, now to just stop the bleeding and...
じゃあ後は止血して
Yes... That's it...
そう そうだよ
Reg...
レグ 大丈夫だよ
I'm... alright...
どく 抜けたら しけつ
After... the poison's out... stop the bleed-
リコ 目を覚ませ
Riko, wake up!
Reg, I'm alright...
レグ 大丈夫だよ
Damn it! Now she's also hallucinating!
くそっ 幻覚が併発している
Is that 'cause we're close to the third layer?!
三層が近いせいか
After I wipe the blood, more streams out...
拭いた後から流れてくる
Calm down!
落ち着け
とにかく傷の具合を
At any rate, I need to check on the wound...
I-it's swelled to several times normal size...
な 何倍に腫れているんだ
H-her glove... I need to take it off.
て 手袋を外さないと
D-did that hurt? Sorry...!
い 痛かったか すまん
Reg...
レグ
Riko! I'm here!
リコ ここだ
It's, uh... too swollen, so I can't get the glove off.
その 腫れすぎていて 手袋が取れない
What should I do?
どうすればいい
What can I do to save you?!
どうすれば君を助けられる
痛むのか 何でも言ってくれ
Does it hurt? Please just say something.
Cut it...
きって
Huh?!
Cut it... off.
きり きり おとし て
A-are you out of your mind, Riko?!
しょ 正気かリコ
If I do that, you'll...!
そんなことをしたら君は
R-Reg...
レグ おねがい
Please...
じゃないと し しんじゃう
If you don't...
I-I'll die...
Reg...
レグ
I'm scared...
こわい こわいよぉ レグ
I'm so scared...
Reg...
Back then...
あの時 もっと リコを後ろに下がらせていれば
if only I had made Riko stay farther behind me...
First...
先に 骨を折っておかないと
you need to break the bone.
A Black Whistle who had this happen...
こうなった黒苗が切るの 大変だったって
said that cutting it off was tough.
Back then...
あの時 火葬砲をさっさと使っていれば
if only I had quickly used my Incinerator...
Back then...
あの時 僕がもっと盾になっていれば
if only I had been a better shield...
This is no time to cry!
泣いてる場合か
The more I hesitate, the more Riko suffers!
たまらった分 リコが苦しむんだぞ
Here it goes, Riko.
行くぞ リコ
Wh-what am I even doing...?
な 何をしているんだ僕は
Reg...
レグ
Don't leave me!
行かないで
Riko! It's me! I'm right here!
リコ 僕だ ここにいるぞ
Don't... go...
行っちゃ いや
Me, too... together... to the netherworld's... bottom...
私も いっひょ
ならく そこに
Riko... your consciousness is already...
リコ もう意識が
I'll definitely take you there!
必ず連れて行ってやる
You've got an awful fever...
すごい熱だ
Don't YOU go and leave ME behind...
君こそ 僕を置いていくな
Hurry...
急げ 急げ
Hurry!
M-my hands are shaking...
て 手が震える
Pull yourself together!
気をしっかり持て
Otherwise, Riko will suffer all the more!
リコが余計に苦しむぞ
Damn you! Don't get in my way!
くそぉ 邪魔するなあ
Not near Riko! Stay away from Riko!
リコに リコによるなぁ
Get outta here!
あっちいけ
Damn it!
くそぉ
She's not breathing!
息してない
Riko!
リコ 息をしてくれ
Please breathe!
Riko! Riko!
リコ リコ
リコ
Riko!
リコ まて
Riko...
hold on...
リコ
Don't leave me behind, Riko!
置いていかないでリコ
Riko!
リコ
Open your eyes!
目を開けてくれ
Please open your eyes!
Riko!
リコ
You're so noisy...
うるさいな
That girl...
そいつ まだ心臓は動いてるよ
Her heart is still beating...
It's likely to stop any moment now, though.
今にも止まりそうだけどな
Wh-what are you?!
な 何者だ
I'm a just a fluffy stuffed doll.
んなぁ ふわふわのぬいぐるみだよ
I've come here to comfort you two...
お前達を慰めに来たんだ
Wh-what?!
な なんだ
誰なんだ お前は
Just who the heck are you?!
I'm happy to properly introduce myself...
丁寧に教えてもいいけどさ
but first wouldn't it be best to hear
about how to save her?
先にそいつ助ける方法聞いたほうがよくね
リ リコ
Riko...
This's quite bad...
んなぁ こりゃ酷い
What should I do...?
どうすれば
Please tell me! I want to save Riko!
教えてくれ
リコを助けたい
What can I do to get her breathing again?!
どうすれば呼吸を戻せる
Just blow a breath directly into her.
お前が直接息を吹き込んでやりゃいい
Like a kiss, you know, a kiss.
ちゅーよちゅー やり方知って
Do you know how?
Like that?!
こいか
That's the way, but go a little slower.
その調子 もう少しゆっくり
And pinch her nose shut.
鼻は塞いでな
Okay!
そうか
Also, tilt up her chin to open her airway.
あと 顎を上げて気道を開けるんだ
じゃないと意味ないぞ
Otherwise, there's no point to this.
Got it!
わかった
She's breathing again.
息が戻った よかった
I'm so glad!
Thank you!
ありがとう 何とお礼を
I can't begin to express my gratitude...
It's still too early to relax.
安心するのはまだ早いぜ
Huh?!
Well, it seems she's not regaining consciousness.
んなぁ 意識が戻らねーな
Th-that can't be!
そ そんな
What should I do?!
どうすれば
Calm down!
落ち着けって
If she was to wake right now,
it's not like she'd be able to bear the pain anyway...
戻った所で痛みに耐えられるわけじゃねーし
But...!
しかし
You, come on and carry the girl back to my hideout.
お前 コイツオイラのアジトまで運びなよ
Huh?
I'll find a way to do something for her...
なんとかしてやる
Really?!
本当か
どこの誰とも知らぬのに
Even though you don't know anything about us?!
Well...
Just keep a little distance between us, okay?
ちょっと 離れてくれね
Still, the way things stand now, her arm will break off...
しかし このままじゃ腕がもげるな
You need to reinforce it,
so hurry and fetch some branches.
お前補強するから 大急ぎで枝集めな
So you can do something about her hand?!
手も何とかできるのか
Understood!
了解した
But let me warn you:
言っとくけど 完全に元通りにはできねーぞ
It's not going to go back to the way it was before.
Jeez, he's not even listening...
って 聞いてねーし
H-hey, hold on!
待ってくれ
Hm?
If I climb up this, Riko will...
こんな所を登ったらリコが
Well, I guess you can't see it then, after all.
んなぁ お前やっぱり 見えてねーのな
Huh? What?
なんだ
What are you talking about?
何を言ってるんだ
Just take it easy.
安心しなよ
The Curse isn't present right now, you see.
今は呪いは「無い」から
If we don't hurry, her whole body
will swell up like her arm has.
急がないと
全身その腕みたいに膨れちゃうぜ
Damn it...
くそ
What is this place...?
なんだ ここは
Cave-raiding equipment...?
探窟の道具
Besides that...
それに
Are those... whistles?
これは 笛か
H-hey... who exactly are you?
な なぁ あんたは一体
Ah! I suppose I never told you my name...
そういや名前も行ってなかったな
I'm Nanachi.
オイラはナナチだ
I'm what you cave raiders would call...
お前ら探窟家が言うところの
「成れ果て」だよ
a Hollow.
Sora ni ukanderu hikaru nami o
空に浮かんでる光る波を束ねて虹の橋をかけよう
Tabanete niji no hashi o kakeyou
危うい足場 滑るスロープ
Ayaui ashiba, suberu slope
Kako to mirai no michishirube
過去と未来の道標
君の左手 僕の右手を
Kimi no hidarite, boku no migite o
Tsunaide tsunagete hajimeyou
繫いで繫げてはじめよう
いつも そばに いるよ
Itsumo soba ni iru yo
過去も 今も 未来も
Kako mo ima mo mirai mo
Dakara mayowazu ni aruiteikou
だから迷わずに歩いていこう
色とりどりの夢 重ねて
Irotoridori no yume kasanete
明日はどこに向かう
Ashita wa doko ni mukau
君と一緒にいれたら 世界は輝きだすよ
Kimi to issho ni iretara, sekai wa kagayakidasu yo
最果ての地に咲く花を探そう
Saihate no chi ni saku hana o sagasou
Next Episode
Nanachi